[
    {
        "question": "وَلَلْآخِرَةُ",
        "answer": "And surely the Hereafter",
        "pcklId": "156",
        "rootWordId": 22,
        "tlit": "walalākhiratu",
        "frequency": "250",
        "surahnum": "93",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَلْآخِرَةُ خَيْرٌ لَكَ مِنَ الْأُولَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آخِر",
        "waznEnglish": "Hereafter, end, last, later generations",
        "waznTlit": "ākhir",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِذَا",
        "answer": "when",
        "pcklId": "397",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "93",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَاللَّيْلِ إِذَا سَجَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَمَّا",
        "answer": "So as for",
        "pcklId": "39",
        "rootWordId": 73,
        "tlit": "fa-ammā",
        "frequency": "55",
        "surahnum": "93",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَمَّا الْيَتِيمَ فَلَا تَقْهَرْ",
        "rootWord": "أَمَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "أَمَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "Then as for",
        "waznTlit": "ammā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Explanation particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَمَّا",
        "answer": "And as for",
        "pcklId": "40",
        "rootWordId": 73,
        "tlit": "wa-ammā",
        "frequency": "55",
        "surahnum": "93",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَمَّا السَّائِلَ فَلَا تَنْهَرْ",
        "rootWord": "أَمَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "أَمَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "Then as for",
        "waznTlit": "ammā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Explanation particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَمَّا",
        "answer": "But as for",
        "pcklId": "41",
        "rootWordId": 73,
        "tlit": "wa-ammā",
        "frequency": "55",
        "surahnum": "93",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَمَّا بِنِعْمَةِ رَبِّكَ فَحَدِّثْ",
        "rootWord": "أَمَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "أَمَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "Then as for",
        "waznTlit": "ammā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Explanation particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأُولَىٰ",
        "answer": "the first",
        "pcklId": "60",
        "rootWordId": 85,
        "tlit": "l-ūlā",
        "frequency": "170",
        "surahnum": "93",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَلْآخِرَةُ خَيْرٌ لَكَ مِنَ الْأُولَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوَّل",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) first",
        "waznTlit": "awwal",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَآوَىٰ",
        "answer": "and give shelter",
        "pcklId": "13",
        "rootWordId": 87,
        "tlit": "faāwā",
        "frequency": "36",
        "surahnum": "93",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَمْ يَجِدْكَ يَتِيمًا فَآوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ءَاوَىٰٓ",
        "waznEnglish": "to give shelter",
        "waznTlit": "āwā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَحَدِّثْ",
        "answer": "narrate",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 297,
        "tlit": "faḥaddith",
        "frequency": "36",
        "surahnum": "93",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَمَّا بِنِعْمَةِ رَبِّكَ فَحَدِّثْ",
        "rootWord": "ح د ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تُحَدِّثُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to report, to narate",
        "waznTlit": "tuḥaddithu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "خَيْرٌ",
        "answer": "(is) better",
        "pcklId": "149",
        "rootWordId": 449,
        "tlit": "khayrun",
        "frequency": "196",
        "surahnum": "93",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَلْآخِرَةُ خَيْرٌ لَكَ مِنَ الْأُولَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "خ ي ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَيْر",
        "waznEnglish": "they select",
        "waznTlit": "khayr",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبُّكَ",
        "answer": "your Lord",
        "pcklId": "956",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbuka",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "93",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " مَا وَدَّعَكَ رَبُّكَ وَمَا قَلَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبُّكَ",
        "answer": "your Lord",
        "pcklId": "957",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbuka",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "93",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَسَوْفَ يُعْطِيكَ رَبُّكَ فَتَرْضَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّكَ",
        "answer": "(of) your Lord",
        "pcklId": "958",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbika",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "93",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَمَّا بِنِعْمَةِ رَبِّكَ فَحَدِّثْ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَتَرْضَىٰ",
        "answer": "then you will be satisfied",
        "pcklId": "35",
        "rootWordId": 561,
        "tlit": "fatarḍā",
        "frequency": "73",
        "surahnum": "93",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَسَوْفَ يُعْطِيكَ رَبُّكَ فَتَرْضَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر ض و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَّضِىَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be pleased",
        "waznTlit": "raḍiya",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّائِلَ",
        "answer": "one who asks",
        "pcklId": "123",
        "rootWordId": 647,
        "tlit": "l-sāila",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "93",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَمَّا السَّائِلَ فَلَا تَنْهَرْ",
        "rootWord": "س أ ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَآئِل",
        "waznEnglish": "you have asked (for)",
        "waznTlit": "sāil",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَجَىٰ",
        "answer": "it covers with darkness",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 663,
        "tlit": "sajā",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "93",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَاللَّيْلِ إِذَا سَجَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "س ج و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "س ج و",
        "waznEnglish": "to cover with darkness",
        "waznTlit": "sīn jīm wāw",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالضُّحَىٰ",
        "answer": "By the morning brightness",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 882,
        "tlit": "wal-ḍuḥā",
        "frequency": "7",
        "surahnum": "93",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالضُّحَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ض ح و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ضُحًى",
        "waznEnglish": "exposed to the sun's heat",
        "waznTlit": "ḍuḥan",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "ضَالًّا",
        "answer": "lost",
        "pcklId": "183",
        "rootWordId": 891,
        "tlit": "ḍāllan",
        "frequency": "191",
        "surahnum": "93",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَوَجَدَكَ ضَالًّا فَهَدَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ض ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ضَآلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "he went astray (from)",
        "waznTlit": "ḍāll",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُعْطِيكَ",
        "answer": "will give you",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 1004,
        "tlit": "yuʿ'ṭīka",
        "frequency": "14",
        "surahnum": "93",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَسَوْفَ يُعْطِيكَ رَبُّكَ فَتَرْضَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ع ط و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَعْطَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to give",
        "waznTlit": "aʿṭā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَائِلًا",
        "answer": "in need",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1045,
        "tlit": "ʿāilan",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "93",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَوَجَدَكَ عَائِلًا فَأَغْنَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ع ي ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَآئِل",
        "waznEnglish": "poverty",
        "waznTlit": "ʿāil",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَغْنَىٰ",
        "answer": "so He made self-sufficient",
        "pcklId": "13",
        "rootWordId": 1086,
        "tlit": "fa-aghnā",
        "frequency": "73",
        "surahnum": "93",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَوَجَدَكَ عَائِلًا فَأَغْنَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "غ ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَغْنَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to avail, to prosper",
        "waznTlit": "aghnā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَلَىٰ",
        "answer": "He is displeased",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1227,
        "tlit": "qalā",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "93",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " مَا وَدَّعَكَ رَبُّكَ وَمَا قَلَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ق ل ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be displeased",
        "waznTlit": "qalā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَقْهَرْ",
        "answer": "oppress",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1240,
        "tlit": "taqhar",
        "frequency": "10",
        "surahnum": "93",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَمَّا الْيَتِيمَ فَلَا تَقْهَرْ",
        "rootWord": "ق ه ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَقْهَرْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to oppress",
        "waznTlit": "taqhar",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَاللَّيْلِ",
        "answer": "And the night",
        "pcklId": "81",
        "rootWordId": 1364,
        "tlit": "wa-al-layli",
        "frequency": "92",
        "surahnum": "93",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَاللَّيْلِ إِذَا سَجَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ل ي ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "لَيْل",
        "waznEnglish": "of the night",
        "waznTlit": "layl",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِنِعْمَةِ",
        "answer": "(the) Favor",
        "pcklId": "119",
        "rootWordId": 1492,
        "tlit": "biniʿ'mati",
        "frequency": "140",
        "surahnum": "93",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَمَّا بِنِعْمَةِ رَبِّكَ فَحَدِّثْ",
        "rootWord": "ن ع م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نِعْمَة",
        "waznEnglish": "then good",
        "waznTlit": "niʿ'mat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَنْهَرْ",
        "answer": "repel",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1525,
        "tlit": "tanhar",
        "frequency": "113",
        "surahnum": "93",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَمَّا السَّائِلَ فَلَا تَنْهَرْ",
        "rootWord": "ن ه ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَنْهَرْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to repel",
        "waznTlit": "tanhar",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَهَدَىٰ",
        "answer": "so He guided",
        "pcklId": "143",
        "rootWordId": 1547,
        "tlit": "fahadā",
        "frequency": "316",
        "surahnum": "93",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَوَجَدَكَ ضَالًّا فَهَدَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ه د ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "هَدَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to guide",
        "waznTlit": "hadā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَجِدْكَ",
        "answer": "He find you",
        "pcklId": "103",
        "rootWordId": 1588,
        "tlit": "yajid'ka",
        "frequency": "107",
        "surahnum": "93",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَمْ يَجِدْكَ يَتِيمًا فَآوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "و ج د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَجَدَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to find",
        "waznTlit": "wajada",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَوَجَدَكَ",
        "answer": "And He found you",
        "pcklId": "104",
        "rootWordId": 1588,
        "tlit": "wawajadaka",
        "frequency": "107",
        "surahnum": "93",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَوَجَدَكَ ضَالًّا فَهَدَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "و ج د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَجَدَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to find",
        "waznTlit": "wajada",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَوَجَدَكَ",
        "answer": "And He found you",
        "pcklId": "105",
        "rootWordId": 1588,
        "tlit": "wawajadaka",
        "frequency": "107",
        "surahnum": "93",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَوَجَدَكَ عَائِلًا فَأَغْنَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "و ج د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَجَدَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to find",
        "waznTlit": "wajada",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَدَّعَكَ",
        "answer": "has forsaken you",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1597,
        "tlit": "waddaʿaka",
        "frequency": "4",
        "surahnum": "93",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " مَا وَدَّعَكَ رَبُّكَ وَمَا قَلَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "و د ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَدَّعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to forsake",
        "waznTlit": "waddaʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَتِيمًا",
        "answer": "an orphan",
        "pcklId": "18",
        "rootWordId": 1656,
        "tlit": "yatīman",
        "frequency": "23",
        "surahnum": "93",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَمْ يَجِدْكَ يَتِيمًا فَآوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ي ت م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي ت م",
        "waznEnglish": "and [the] orphans",
        "waznTlit": "yā tā mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْيَتِيمَ",
        "answer": "the orphan",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 1656,
        "tlit": "l-yatīma",
        "frequency": "23",
        "surahnum": "93",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَمَّا الْيَتِيمَ فَلَا تَقْهَرْ",
        "rootWord": "ي ت م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي ت م",
        "waznEnglish": "and [the] orphans",
        "waznTlit": "yā tā mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    }
]